Guide to the Daniel Huntington Study Portrait Photographs Collection ca. 1870-1890 PR 256
New-York Historical Society
- Portraits
  - unspecified
    - Vanderpoel, Aaron (1799-1870), judge (Box Unknown container 434 for instance of Vanderpoel, Aaron (1799-1870), judge, Folder unknown container)
    - Warren, John (1799-1878), stockbroker (Box Unknown container 435 for instance of Warren, John (1799-1878), stockbroker, Folder 11)
      On verso: Prest of Board of Brokers (Stock Exchange)
    - Warren, J. Kearney (d. 1895) (Box Unknown container 436 for instance of Warren, J. Kearney (d. 1895), Folder unknown container)
    - Washburn, Edward Abiel (1819-1881), clergyman (Box Unknown container 437 for instance of Washburn, Edward Abiel (1819-1881), clergyman, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: of Calvary Church
    - Weir, Robert Walter (1803-1889), painter (Box Unknown container 438 for instance of Weir, Robert Walter (1803-1889), painter, Folder unknown container)
    - Whipple, Henry B., Rev. (1822-1901), clergyman (Box Unknown container 439 for instance of Whipple, Henry B., Rev. (1822-1901), clergyman, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: Bishop / He said "it looked like a Methodist parson" yet it is a tremendous likeness D.H.
    - White, Andrew Dickson (1832-1918), diplomat (Box Unknown container 440 for instance of White, Andrew Dickson (1832-1918), diplomat, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: President of Cornell about 1890, minister to Germany 1899
    - White, Chandler (d. 1856) [from a daguerreotype] (Box Unknown container 441 for instance of White, Chandler (d. 1856) [from a daguerreotype], Folder unknown container)
      On verso: of the first Cable Syndicate This is from an old daguerreotype of the only likeness to be found of him
    - Whittingham, William Rollison (1805-1879), clergyman, Bishop of Maryland (Box Unknown container 442 for instance of Whittingham, William Rollison (1805-1879), clergyman, Bishop of Maryland, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: This is severe (as it should be) from the Daguerreotype / fine for character (but it was very hot weather & his shirt-collar showed it)! (not a bad Savonarola) D.H.
    - Williams, John S. (1814-1876), businessman (Box Unknown container 443 for instance of Williams, John S. (1814-1876), businessman, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: of Williams & Guyon [Guion]
    - Winthrop, Robert (1832-1892), banker (Box Unknown container 444 for instance of Winthrop, Robert (1832-1892), banker, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: of New York
    - Winthrop, Robert Charles (1809-1894), lawyer [2 images] (Box Unknown container 445 for instance of Winthrop, Robert Charles (1809-1894), lawyer [2 images], Folder unknown container)
      On verso #1: very good before he began to grow feeble
    - Wolfe, John David (1792-1872), merchant [2 images] (Box Unknown container 446 for instance of Wolfe, John David (1792-1872), merchant [2 images], Folder unknown container)
    - Woodruff, Lewis Bartholomew (1809-1875), judge (Box Unknown container 447 for instance of Woodruff, Lewis Bartholomew (1809-1875), judge, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: Lewis B. US Circuit Court
    - Washburn, Edward Abiel (1819-1881), clergyman (Box Unknown container 448 for instance of Washburn, Edward Abiel (1819-1881), clergyman, Folder unknown container)
    - Washburn, Edward Abiel (1819-1881), clergyman (Box Unknown container 449 for instance of Washburn, Edward Abiel (1819-1881), clergyman, Folder unknown container)
- Oversize Portraits
  Filed alphabetically by sitter; life dates and vocations were added during processing.
  - unspecified
    - Fry, Charles M. (1822-1892), merchant, bank president (Box Unknown container 450 for instance of Fry, Charles M. (1822-1892), merchant, bank president, Folder 12)
      On verso: President of Bank of NY taken about 1888-90 he died Nov 1892
    - Gardiner, John Lyon (1841-1910), gentleman (Box Unknown container 451 for instance of Gardiner, John Lyon (1841-1910), gentleman, Folder unknown container)
    - Gracie, James King (1840-1903), philanthropist (Box Unknown container 452 for instance of Gracie, James King (1840-1903), philanthropist, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: 1878
    - Johnston, John Taylor (1820-1893), railroad president (Box Unknown container 453 for instance of Johnston, John Taylor (1820-1893), railroad president, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: Capital Likeness DH
    - McLane, James Woods (1839-1912), doctor, educator (Box Unknown container 454 for instance of McLane, James Woods (1839-1912), doctor, educator, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: June 1898 / Dr. J.W. McLane / Pres of Trustees College Physicians & Surgeons / James W. McLane MD
    - Pruyn, Robert Lansing (1852-1906), businessman (Box Unknown container 455 for instance of Pruyn, Robert Lansing (1852-1906), businessman, Folder unknown container)
    - Taft, Alphonso (1810-1891), politician (Box Unknown container 456 for instance of Taft, Alphonso (1810-1891), politician, Folder unknown container)
    - Tracy, Edward H. (d. 1875), engineer (Box Unknown container 457 for instance of Tracy, Edward H. (d. 1875), engineer, Folder unknown container)
    - Trimble, George Thomas (1793-1872), merchant (Box Unknown container 458 for instance of Trimble, George Thomas (1793-1872), merchant, Folder unknown container)
      On verso: NY Hospital?
    - Weir, Robert Walter (1803-1889), painter (Box Unknown container 459 for instance of Weir, Robert Walter (1803-1889), painter, Folder unknown container)